NATALY MENARES

(650) 250-6864 nataly.menares@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Github</u> <u>Portfolio</u>

SKILLS

More than 4 years working as a software engineer and using different frameworks and tools such as JavaScript, Vue.js, Ember.js, d3.js, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, SQL,BigQuery, Firebase, Postgres, Tableau.

Basic knowledge in React.js, Redux, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Python, Google Analytics, Google Cloud.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack - Software Developer (100% Remote)

MikMak, @New York, NY, US.

Jun 2021 - Present

- Lead and implement new features using **Vue.js** framework and other libraries like **d3.js** to create charts from scratch
- Work with REST APIs and queries to get information from databases.
- Code Jest unit-tests and dispatch and analyze logs on Amplitude and Datadog to debug, understand product performance and user experience.

Frontend - Software Developer

Lore 10, @Sunnyvale, CA, US.

Jan 2019 - Jun 2021

- Design and develop new frontend features using **Ember.js** framework.
- Improve frontend application loading performance by 50% in the last year.
- Propose and implement User Experience workflow improvements.

Marketing Engineer - Remote

SimpliRoute, @San Jose, CA, US.

Jan 2017 - May 2018

- Analyze market keywords to manage Adwords Campaigns and apply SEO techniques, resulting in 100% increase in demo requests within the first three months and reaching more than 300 new users monthly.
- Create Tableau dashboards to keep the company informed about marketing action-results.

Project Manager

Telefonica, @Santiago, Chile.

Aug 2015 - Sep 2016

- Manage Push Notification Advertising Campaigns, increasing related revenue by 500% through high quality data sets.
- Lead five projects at the same time, working side by side with technical teams from Telefonica and partner companies.
- Teach useful database skills and tools to colleagues to extract useful information about their projects and products.

Data Analyst

Telefonica, @Santiago, Chile.

Oct 2013 - Aug 2015

- Work side by side with three softwares developers and evidence (by experimental real time campaigns and data analysis) how important it was to build a Big Data area in the company.
- Work directly with Project and Product Managers to help them to get data and information to make relevant decisions about their projects.

PROJECTS

SomeWays Live Site | Github

JavaScript Project: Maze game, developed using JavaScript, HTML5 and CSS3.

- Used HTML5 canvas to draw and manage the main elements of the game: maze and ball.
- Implemented a maze generation algorithm such that a user can move a ball through the maze.
- The maze is created using cell-logic inside a matrix. Once the first cell is chosen randomly -among a pull of available options- the other options are blocked, the new position is the chosen cell, and it is time to pick the next one,

repeating the process.

• Added different DOM Event listeners to simultaneously manage the one minute timer and the user's actions, such as ball movements and button inputs.

Knitting With Strangers

Live Site | Github

Full Stack clone of <u>Tea With Strangers</u> website with extra features, developed using Ruby for Backend and React-Redux for Frontend.

- Implemented CRUD API in Ruby on Rails to power the React frontend: Users can create a Knitting Time or book/cancel a spot in an existing one. Also, any Knitting Time can be updated or deleted by its host.
- Used React Router for seamless transitions between different sections of the site.
- Added modals using Redux to update Knitting Times description and view Host Profile.

EDUCATION

App Academy - Immersive software development course with focus on full stack web development (Summer 2018)

Universidad Diego Portales @Santiago, Chile - M.Sc - Marketing Management (2015 - 2017)

Universidad de Chile @Santiago, Chile - B.Sc. - Industrial Engineering (2006 - 2012)